#### Solomon P Mwalupani





### **ABOUT**

Full-stack Software Developer, back-end heavy with 2+ years of experience using technologies such as PHP(Laravel), Java(Spring boot), Dart(Flutter), TypeScripts and JavaScript(AngularJS), MySQL, MongoDB, Git, HTML, and CSS. Detail-oriented, well organized, team worker, hard worker, and capable to come up with an idea and inspire others. Also, Develop awesome web applications both frontend and backend, create a web application interface that creates an emotional connection with audiences. Use the latest technologies and tools in delivering web application development and designing across platforms.

SEX : MALE

NATIONALITY: TANZANIAN

**DATE OF BIRTH**: 01<sup>st</sup> January, 2000

MARITAL STATUS : SINGLE

LANGUAGES : SWAHILI, ENGLISH



### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor Degree | MZUMBE UNIVERSITY MOROGORO (FACULTY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY)

**Discipline:** BSc Information Technology and Systems

Certificate: Degree of Bachelor of Science in Information Technology and

Systems 2020 – 2023

Advanced Level Education | SINAI SECONDARY SCHOOL

**Combination:** EGM

Certificate: Advanced Certificate of Secondary Education Examination (ACSEE) 2018 -

2020

Ordinary Level Education | MATEMA BEACH HIGH SCHOOL Certificate: Certificate of Secondary Education (CSEE) 2014 -

2017

Primary Education | ISIMBA PRIMARY SCHOOL (2007-2013

**Certificate:** Certificate of Primary Education



- Strong problem-solving skills
- Excellent interpersonal and communication abilities
- Ability to work effectively with cross-functional teams
- Experience in database design and flexible working with MySQL databases.
- Source and Version Control (GitHub, BitBucket)
- Software Documentation Control.
- Development programming tools Intellij IDEA, Sublime, VS Code, Android studio, Postman, ThunderClient.
- Design and implement APIs to facilitate seamless data exchange between front-end and back-end systems.
- Create and optimize database schemas, queries, and data models with MySQL



### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Software Developer | Pessors Company Limited.** 

Location: Mbezi Beach, Dar-es-Salaam, Tanzania (Part Time).

Website: <a href="https://atlais.org/">https://atlais.org/</a>
Website: <a href="https://pesaby.com">https://pesaby.com</a>
Duration: 2023 – CURRENT

#### **ACTIVITIES**

- Working on Atlais Project as Full Stack Software Developer and I manage Atlais hosting server ensuring everything work perfectly.
- We create databases for churches, Microfinances and various prevalent Organizations.
- Acts as a systems administrator, and performed administration on Shared Hosting. Hosted systems, and configured a Shared server.
- Developed SMS sending Back-end.
- · Performs software maintenance.
- Website Maintenance of both atlais and pesaby mobile App sites.

Tech: PHP/Laravel and WordPress.

# **Software Developer | Tronestech Ltd.**

Location: Mikocheni Beach, Dar-es-Salaam, Tanzania (Remote).

Website: <a href="https://mauzo360.com/">https://mauzo360.com/</a> **Duration:** 20/8/2023 – 20/10/2023

#### **ACTIVITIES**

Working on Mauzo360 Project as Full Stack Software Developer

Performs software maintenance.

Tech: PHP/Codelgniter.



# **OTHER ACTIVITIES**

**Software Developer | Freelancer** 

**Location:** Mzumbe University, Morogoro, Tanzania.

Website: <a href="https://solo.co.tz/">https://solo.co.tz/</a>

Website: <a href="https://sologroup.solo.co.tz">https://sologroup.solo.co.tz</a>

**Duration:** 2022 – 2023

Project Name: FARM PRODUCTION MANAGEMENT SYSTEM (STUDENT FINAL YEAR

PROJECT)

Project Link: <a href="https://fpms.solo.co.tz">https://fpms.solo.co.tz</a>

**Summary:** The fpms system will control and manage all details of farm in farming activities

Link <a href="https://fpms.solo.co.tz">https://fpms.solo.co.tz</a> for demo test ----- admin credentials username: <a href="mailto:mwalupani@gmail.com">mwalupani@gmail.com</a> password: solomon12 but user credentials username: <a href="mailto:jenina@gmail.com">jenina@gmail.com</a> password: solomon12

Roles: I worked alone on this and hosted to server.

**TECHS: Laravel and AngularJS.** 

#### **Software Developer | Freelancer**

Location: Mzumbe University, Morogoro, Tanzania.

Website: <a href="https://solo.co.tz/">https://solo.co.tz/</a>

Website: <a href="https://sologroup.solo.co.tz">https://sologroup.solo.co.tz</a>

**Duration:** 2023-Current

**Project Name: ONLINE BIRTH CERTIFICATE SYSTEM** 

**Summary:** <a href="https://github.com/solomoni12/OBCS">https://github.com/solomoni12/OBCS</a>. Online Birth Certificate Project with Laravel Framework (backend), Angular 14 Framework (frontend) and MySQL for Database. Online Birth

Certificate System (OBCS) maintains a good record of date of birth of people. This system helps admin to view data of date of birth of people who reside in country. The main objective of "Online Birth Certificate System" project is to providing privacy and easier registration of date of birth and gets certificate of birth online which save lots of time.

Roles: Worked alone on this.

**TECHS: PHP/Laravel and AngularJs.** 

**GITHUB CV** 

https://github.com/solomoni12/SolomonMwalupani\_CV

# **REFEREES**

Name: Mr. Lunodzo Mwinuka Position: Assistant Lecturer

**Organization: Mzumbe University** 

Phone: (+255) 765268371

Email: <u>lumwinuka@mzumbe.ac.tz</u>

Name: Dr. Simeo Kisanjara

**Position: Lecturer** 

**Organization: Mzumbe University** 

Phone: (+255) 784727735

Email: <a href="mailto:sbkisanjara@mzumbe.ac.tz">sbkisanjara@mzumbe.ac.tz</a>

Name: Japhari Mbaru

**Position: Software Developer** 

**Organization: Tami semi** 

president office.

Phone: (+255) 714076404

Email: japharimbaru@tamisemi.go.tz